<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-11T11:45:49+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Arden’s Corner</title><subtitle>Arden Chan's Personal Website</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Lonely Travels: [20 Jul 2021] Silang, feat. Cafe Agapita</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/08/01/10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lonely Travels: [20 Jul 2021] Silang, feat. Cafe Agapita" /><published>2021-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-08-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/08/01/10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/08/01/10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita.html">&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/2021/07/12/lonely-travels-tagaytay-silang-6x7-jul-2021/&quot;&gt;Tagaytay+Silang entry&lt;/a&gt;, I want to explore Silang as it looks like a nice quaint town. Well, I did that on the spur of the moment last 20 Jul 2021. On that day, exploring Silang was nagging my mind and I was quite bored so I gave it a go. My rough goal was visiting Cafe Agapita, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/results?search_query=cafe+agapita&quot;&gt;quite popular with YouTube vloggers&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silang is about 15 minutes away from Dasmariñas by jeepney. As quite common when I go to places I don’t know well, I got off a long way from the place, getting off at the Silang welcome arch. It’s fortunate that I did though, as the street leading to the town is very nice to walk through. It’s cloudy, windy, and cool, so even though it’s 15:30 I had a nice, long walk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0083.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0083.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Random pic of the street. Notice the greenery?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0084.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0084.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Another random pic of the street. Road is almost deserted.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way is the Silang branch of Cavite State University. Compared to other state universities, it’s on the tiny/small side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0085.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0085.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Street (boulevard?) leading to the university.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0087.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0087.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Another view of the University (the white building in the distance).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walked to the university but did not go all the way in. No one stopped me, but with the pandemic and the fact I’m not an alumni discouraged me from further exploration. Time is not on my side either, as it’s already 15:30 and I don’t have the luxury of staying late. There were also roaming dogs, so no dice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside the university is the still-being-constructed new Silang municipal hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0090.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0090.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;New Silang municipal building, still under construction.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 20 minutes later, I arrive at the cafe. The drizzle’s getting stronger, progressing to torrential rain once I’m inside.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0099.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0099.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Internal road leading to the actual cafe entrance.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0093.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0093.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Guests waiting area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place is quite packed, and I immediately regretted coming. I’m not for crowds; I enjoy most when an establishment has almost no people in it. After 5-10 minutes I was let inside. It’s literally a dining hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0097-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0097-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Dining hall from my table. Don’t mind the dishes; I took this pic after I ate.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0098.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0098.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Another view of the dining hall.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As feared, no corner tables are available, and you can’t really choose because all’s taken. So here I am quite near the center, seating awkwardly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They have a QR code at the table’s corner, which when scanned gives you their online menu. Or rather, it leads you to &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1XiJ7gut2A4mlmWEqX77vEgbs57OYK3_Y&quot;&gt;their Google Drive&lt;/a&gt;. Strange, I know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I ordered myself an espresso shot and a plate of Tuna Aglio Olio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0094-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0094-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Espresso shot, ₱65.00.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/08/dji_0096.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-08-01-10-04-39-Lonely_Travels_20_Jul_2021_Silang_feat._Cafe_Agapita/dji_0096.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Tuna Aglio Olio, ₱225.00.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Impressions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food-wise, it’s okay. It’s not stellar, but is not bad. I quite liked the Tuna Aglio Olio and ended up ordering another serving.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Service-wise, it’s not bad but not good either, and I felt I was being ignored. Perhaps because I was not in my best clothes? I don’t know about you, but I’m quite ticked off when people judge your paying capacity by your external appearance. Or maybe because they’re just so many customers and I’m just being a Karen? Notable is I asked for service water about five times before I received two glasses, and there were insects (gasp!) on the second one. Not a good experience; reminds me of how Dasmariñas clerks treat customers who look like they don’t have a lot of money.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Place-wise, this is obviously an events place, meaning you go here mainly for the ambiance. This is mainly the reason why it’s popular with YouTube and Instagram people, because of the lush surroundings which looks good on videos and selfies. You can literally dine under the trees; unfortunately it’s raining quite hard on that day so everyone’s packed inside the “gymnasium”. It’s ideal for receptions, social gatherings, and photoshoots; those are literally advertised on &lt;a href=&quot;https://cafeagapita.com/&quot;&gt;their website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My verdict: if you are after instagrammable pics, you will enjoy your time here. But if you’re mainly after the food and service, which I was, then you might not want to eat here, as the food is quite forgettable and service is a bit so-so. Case in point: even though I liked the Tuna Aglio Olio, I can’t remember how it tastes like; same is true for the espresso shot. Honestly, place-wise I had more fun in Forastero Cafe, while food-wise Don Juan Restaurant is great (and cheaper!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, after an hour I left and proceeded to do a little more exploration, which I found difficult due to the torrential rain. No pics from here on out, I’m afraid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking the vicinity of Cafe Agapita made me regret more getting my fill there, as there were many other restaurants I could have tried. I would say Cafe Agapita is like the Starbucks of Silang: the main clientele are people who want to show they can afford to eat in a “luxurious” place, popular with teenagers who splurge their parents’ money, and with netizens who mainly value the surroundings. And like Starbucks, once you’ve had one, you pretty much had it all. And it’s not even good coffee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, by around 18:00 I was on my way back home to Dasmariñas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will I visit Silang again? Definitely; I would love to try biking all the way there. As for Cafe Agapita? Well, if someone treats me or as part of a social gathering, then yes I might go back, but on my own I would not. I do like the place (as I am a nature lover), but unfortunately it’s not good enough to go back. Brewed Awakening is more picturesque than Cafe Agapita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PS: Don’t think I’m hating on Cafe Agapita, because I’m not. It’s just overrated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Travels" /><category term="cafe agapita" /><category term="cavite state university silang branch" /><category term="lonely travels" /><category term="silang" /><category term="silang new municipal hall" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lonely Travels: [02 Jul 2021] Bike Ride: Sampaloc Avenue, Dasmariñas Cavite</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2021/07/29/12-26-26-Lonely_Travels_02_Jul_2021_Bike_Ride_Sampaloc_Avenue_Dasmari%C3%B1as_Cavite.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lonely Travels: [02 Jul 2021] Bike Ride: Sampaloc Avenue, Dasmariñas Cavite" /><published>2021-07-29T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2021/07/29/12-26-26-Lonely_Travels_02_Jul_2021_Bike_Ride_Sampaloc_Avenue_Dasmari%C3%B1as_Cavite</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2021/07/29/12-26-26-Lonely_Travels_02_Jul_2021_Bike_Ride_Sampaloc_Avenue_Dasmari%C3%B1as_Cavite.html">&lt;p&gt;I like to explore random back roads. Last 02 July, while biking I explored this brand new road still under construction. Google Maps has not reflected it on their maps yet; here it is on OpenStreetMap:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/road.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-29-12-26-26-Lonely_Travels_02_Jul_2021_Bike_Ride_Sampaloc_Avenue_Dasmari%C3%B1as_Cavite/road.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Sampaloc Avenue, Dasmariñas, Cavite. OpenStreetMap link: https://www.openstreetmap.org/#map=16/14.2892/120.9642&amp;amp;layers=CG&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then maybe, Google Maps is just slow to update their map on this side of the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you could see, it’s supposed to connect to the other side of the road (that one is a main road going to Silang). It is still under construction as of 29 Jul 2021, and is not yet open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just purchased an action cam during that time, allowing me to take this footage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/HJU5ThFLvo4 &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may observe:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The sky’s a bit hazy. This is during the time Taal volcano’s vog is quite prominent.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the color’s quite dull, my camera is in D-Cinelike color mode. I’ve since turned it off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was chased by dogs three times. What quite ticked me off is that instead of helping me with the dogs, a worker essentially blamed me for being chased because “I keep returning”. Well duh, it’s quite difficult to exit when there are dogs chasing you, and I can’t really exit the other side because the road’s not yet finished (as you can also see in the video). Anyhow, I managed to brave through the dogs. They don’t look rabid, just angry, and most likely strays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Excluding the dogs and the shitty worker, the ride was quite pleasant. I do hope that this road gets finished soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Uncategorized" /><category term="Cavite" /><category term="Dasmariñas" /><category term="road bike" /><category term="sampaloc avenue" /><category term="travel" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Lonely Travels: [6x7 Jul 2021] Tagaytay + Silang</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/07/11/16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lonely Travels: [6x7 Jul 2021] Tagaytay + Silang" /><published>2021-07-11T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-07-11T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/07/11/16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/travels/2021/07/11/16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang.html">&lt;p&gt;July 6 is my birthday, and I gifted myself a staycation in Tagaytay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who do not know, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tagaytay&quot;&gt;Tagaytay&lt;/a&gt; is a city in Cavite province of the Philippines. It is a popular tourist destination south of Manila, famous for its cool climate due to its elevation. It is also nearer to Manila than is Baguio, another famous place in the north for the same reason. Do note that Baguio is higher (and consequently cooler) than Tagaytay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’s the plan, you might ask? Nothing really; I just want to go someplace. I don’t have an itinerary, and I don’t know where to go. So randomly walking around it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, by the way Tagaytay is close to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taal_Volcano&quot;&gt;Taal volcano&lt;/a&gt;, which is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2020%E2%80%932021_Taal_Volcano_eruptions&quot;&gt;actively erupting&lt;/a&gt; then. It’s not as intense as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rappler.com/newsbreak/iq/timeline-taal-volcano-eruption-2020&quot;&gt;last 2020&lt;/a&gt;, so no dramatic video/pictures. Twisted as it is, I was quite hoping for more spectacular events while I’m there, perhaps something 2020-like. I’m morbid like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I booked a hotel at Reddoorz at least a week before. The place is not expensive; I was able to book the place at around ₱1000.00. Here is the place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[googlemaps https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d3868.86027360692!2d120.98880741434513!3d14.144311091888364!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x33bd7ba3fb4830c1%3A0x2a23a98e70879e9!2sRedDoorz%20%40%20Tagaytay%20Road!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sph!4v1625575054284!5m2!1sen!2sph&amp;amp;amp;w=600&amp;amp;amp;h=450]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the place looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0046.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is dji_0046.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Front&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0044.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is dji_0044.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Looking towards the street&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0045.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is dji_0045.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My unit&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note that I am not endorsing Reddoorz, nor they sponsored this post. One can dream. 😀&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day started when I arrived in Tagaytay around 08:00. It’s quite early and hotel check-in is 14:00, so I just randomly walked a short segment of the road going to Batangas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/HlEYJxx0iZk &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The volcano’s not clearly visible in these clips, but I hope you can see the big smokey plume. I overheard those are sulfur emissions; the air did smell a bit sulfur-y but not oppressively so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, breakfast at a nearby McDonald’s. They had balcony seats overlooking Taal lake, but unfortunately they’re all occupied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another random walk led me to Brewed Awakening. Similar to McDonald’s, they had huts overlooking the lake, which enabled me to get these pictures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/image-1.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/image-1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The volcano is obscured by a tree. Yes, I suck at taking pictures.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/image-2.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/image-2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/image-3.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/image-3.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The waitress convinced me to have a second breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/image-4.jpeg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/image-4.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kapeng barako, macapuno and jackfruit tarts while overlooking an erupting volcano. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Word of advice: to maximise worth of food expenses, do not eat at fast food establishments. Instead, find local eateries, carinderias, or local sari-sari stores and purchase your food from there. Yes, they can potentially be more expensive than global fast food chains, but you get the benefit of trying out local cuisine and experience local customer service (as opposed to generic run-of-the-mill fodder). I can’t recommend this at Dasmariñas however as people there can be quite rude, but that’s another story for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it is just around 10:00 when I finished, I decided to walk all the way to People’s Park in the Sky. According to Google Maps, that’s almost two hours walk from the cafe, a great way to kill time (remember, hotel check-in is 14:00).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Took again random pictures along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0029.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is dji_0029.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0030.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This image has an empty alt attribute; its file name is dji_0030.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might have noticed by now, I like to take back roads and nature-y pictures. And yes, I suck at photography, thank you very much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 11:00, I was near Tagaytay City market. Seeing as it’s near the Reddoorz hotel, I decide to visit the hotel first. By the time I arrived at the hotel, it was 11:30, and I was informed that early check-in will cost ₱200/hour. A bit excessive, so I walked to Tagaytay Picnic Grove to pass the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time I arrived at the entrance of the grove, I was tired and quite hungry. I contemplated going inside the grove and seeking food stalls, but for some reason I didn’t have the courage to. I walked aimlessly around the vicinity for a while. Getting frustrated with myself, I went back to the hotel, killing another 26 minutes and logging an additional 1.9km. At this point, I must have walked at least 9km, including all detours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around 12:30 when I reached Leonarda’s Restaurant with Bed &amp;amp; Breakfast for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0034.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0034.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Inside the restaurant, while waiting for the food.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0035.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0035.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here is my lunch: solo pancit canton, costing ₱120:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0036.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0036.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s decent enough, not bad but nothing to write home about. It did accomplish the job of banishing hunger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I checked in at the hotel at 14:00. Here are some photos of the room’s interior:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0065.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0065.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The bed after I slept in it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0066.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0066.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The bathroom.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bath towel and basic toiletries were provided, plus two bottles of mineral water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0043.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0043.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Basic toiletries: two bath towels, two toothbrushes, one very small toothpaste tube, one very small container of 3-in-1 shampoo+conditioner+body wash, four cotton buds, and one roll of toilet paper. If you’re wondering if this is intended for two persons, it’s because it is. I alone am renting the place.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The room is quite comfy and cold, even without the AC turned on. In fact, I did not use it at all except for the last hour of my stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a 28-32in TV (not sure of the actual size) in the room with a USB stick plugged in, containing several music videos and movies. To pass the time I watched &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt12588448/&quot;&gt;The Larva Island Movie&lt;/a&gt;. The movie is definitely for children, and is quite good if you just want to rest your brain or you’re a fan of fanfics based off of English-dubbed anime. I wholeheartedly agree with its IMDB rating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All this time I want to take a bath but can’t until I have a bar of soap. You might ask: why not use the free 3-in-1 shampoo+conditioner+body wash? Two answers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One: have you seen how small it is?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/bath_liquid.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/bath_liquid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;It’s so small, it almost fits inside my action camera’s cage. It’s 30ml.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two: I don’t have a washcloth to smear its contents into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 16:30, while still drizzling I went out to buy soap. Walking along Santa Rosa - Tagaytay road, I managed to reach 7-Eleven (a cool 2.5km) and bought my soap from there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turning back, the drizzle got stronger until it became full-fledged rain. Quickly needing someplace to wait for the rain to pass, I had early dinner at Don Juan Restaurant (it was around 17:30).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0041.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0041.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Inside the restaurant. I was the only customer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0039.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0039.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Outside view from my table.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ordered pork bbq and garlic rice for a total of ₱224.60 (service charge is ₱9.60).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0037.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0037.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;My meal. I was served 4pcs of bbq total, served in a bed of napa cabbage.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food is really nice, especially the vinegar dip which completes the bbq. It’s quite pinkish in color. Could someone tell which vinegar variant is this, or whatever they mixed in it? It’s so good, I would want a bottle of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0042.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0042.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The heavenly vinegar. Please gimme a bottle or the recipe.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The service is not so good however. Not downright horrible, but not as welcoming as the one in Brewed Awakening or the hotel staff. Maybe because I look like a wet hobo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After at least an hour in the restaurant, I walked back to the hotel. I think I reached it around 19:00. By this time, my legs and thighs are hurting and one of my toes has a blister. I had a nice hot shower with my hard-earned soap bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hotel advertised free WiFi. According to speedtest.net, I had 30mbps down and similar up, which is quite similar to what I have at home. Unfortunately, it does not reach inside the room. Fortunately, every room has a mini balcony in front of it (you can see them in the pictures above). After blogging for a bit and watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/title/tt3794354/?ref_=nv_sr_srsg_0&quot;&gt;Sonic the Hedgehog&lt;/a&gt; from the all-mighty USB stick, I managed to fall asleep around 23:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sleep was not deep however, as it is so cold! AC is off, but it feels like 20°C even under the covers. I woke up around 04:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 05:20, legs and thighs still aching, I walked outside for breakfast. It was foggy and cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0047.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0047.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Santa Rosa - Tagaytay Road at 05:29. Still quite deserted, which I like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0050.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0050.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;An empty lot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0054.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0054.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Road to Picnic Grove. Mysterious and lovely.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got curious yesterday of the opposite road going to Silang (Google Maps says it’s going to Brgy Balite 1), so I went there in search of someplace to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0056.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0056.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The aforementioned road. Quaint; much like.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found a sari-sari store (sorry, I forgot to record the name) where I had breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0059.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0059.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Breakfast: instant coffee and 2pcs ensaimada. ₱27 total.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0058.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0058.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The street across the sari-sari store.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A cheap breakfast with a dog (yes, a stray joined me) in front of a gorgeous view. Nice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After breakfast, I wanted to explore the street more, but several dogs at a distance discouraged me. Going back, I was treated to a gorgeous sunrise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0060.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0060.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Road to Picnic Grove, sunrise. Great start for a great day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0061.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0061.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A more direct view of the sunrise from the same intersection.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free dessert, whee!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, stayed at the hotel until checking out around 11:30. Since my thighs are still aching, I took a tricycle to Fora mall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/zczJ\_N-nom0 &quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ride took a total of 8 minutes, 30 seconds and cost ₱80.00. And I walked the path for almost 2 hours! Even the driver was shocked when I told him that. No wonder, he pretty much took the same path as I did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then rode a jeepney to Robinsons Silang, and had my lunch at Lots’a Pizza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0071.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0071.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Great Manhattan large pizza from Lots’a Pizza, ₱295. Great substitute for more expensive pizza chains like Shakey’s or Pizza Hut (yuck!).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember my earlier rant about prioritising local food over fast food chains? Well, I was planning on eating at Cafe Agapita, but it’s a 26 minute walk from the mall which I couldn’t make due to my aching feet. And it’s already 12:00 and I’m hungry, so cheap fast food it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I explored the mall and its surroundings after lunch. Bought two Bob Ong books at Pandayan Bookstore and got a massage at Vibes around 14:00. By 15:30, I convinced myself to try walking towards Cafe Agapita for some coffee (Lots’a Pizza didn’t have one).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking around the town proper, I can’t help but notice that Silang is quite an interesting place. It is bike-friendly: roads are mostly two lanes and slow (not traffic-prone, but does not encourage high velocity). I also saw quite a lot of bikers. There were also several bike shops scattered around. The atmosphere also feels like being in a bustling small town. For those who can relate, it’s like Lupao, Nueva Ecija. I look forward to exploring more of this town and Silang as a whole; maybe I can make this my next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 16:00, I kinda want some noms. I got curious by the Forastero Cafe, so I went in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0072.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0072.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Inside Forastero Cafe. Sorry for the flares; it might be the dirty lens piece.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had the large iced coffee and sour cream fries, for a total of ₱195. Not bad: coffee is great though fries is quite on the sweet side (which is weird considering it’s sour cream). Don’t be fooled by the dodgy-looking storefront; this is a hidden gem. I will always choose this over Starbucks, as I don’t like paying for overpriced shitty brown caffeinated water for pretentious people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 17:30 I was walking again, this time looking for a ride home. Boarding a jeepney, I was in SM Dasmariñas by 18:00.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2021/07/dji_0076.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2021-07-11-16-39-15-Lonely_Travels_6x7_Jul_2021_Tagaytay__Silang/dji_0076.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;SM Dasmariñas by 18:26.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this concludes the end of my staycation/food trip/walking adventure. I hope you enjoyed it as much I did. ‘Til next time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who are wondering how much this cost, I estimate around ₱4000 for the two whole days, including the hotel. Excluding the hotel, most of my expenses went into food, since as you might have garnered I didn’t put in too much effort on minimising. If you want the same experience but for cheaper (future reminder for me!), I suggest:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accommodation: choose a cheap one. This is Tagaytay after all: explore the outdoors, don’t stay indoors. I believe there are much cheaper options than Reddoorz; I saw some cheap hotels lining the roads.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Transportation: Biking instead of taking a car/motorcycle or public transportation. Bicycles don’t require purchasing fossil fuels, fattens the wallet, helps the environment, and slims down tummies. Biking to Tagaytay is a popular activity regardless of your starting point, as well as riding around the city regardless the time of day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food: as most backpackers and thrifty travelers will tell you, bringing or cooking your own food is a great way to minimise food expense. A second alternative is to buy from sari-sari stores and carinderias: not only they’re a bit cheaper than full-blown restaurants, you’re also helping local businesses. Just choose clean-looking ones and use your common sense; after all, medical bills are still more expensive than a meal at a five-star restaurant.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Entertainment: Come on, this is Tagaytay; sight-seeing is free! Enjoy the cool weather and the trees whether under them or looking from a distance. Especially if you’re coming from urban jungles like Manila: experience real nature rather than fake ones at malls. Speaking of…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Malls: avoid them. Granted, most here are owned by Ayala which guarantees a top-notch experience, but really, malls? Personally, I would rather recommend you walk along the main roads of Tagaytay than walking inside malls, as you can see more exciting things at the roadside (like Taal volcano) than inside a mall. Go to a mall because you need to buy something, not because you “need” to. And even then I would like you go to Mahogany Beef Market &amp;amp; Bulalohan instead. But if you want a crappy Tagaytay excursion then by all means you do you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Travels" /><category term="silang" /><category term="staycation" /><category term="tagaytay" /><category term="travel" /><summary type="html">Tagaytay staycation/food trip/walking adventure, 06x07 Jul 2021.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2014 in review</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2015/01/24/06-30-48-2014_in_review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2014 in review" /><published>2015-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-01-24T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2015/01/24/06-30-48-2014_in_review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2015/01/24/06-30-48-2014_in_review.html">&lt;p&gt;Some filler while I think of blogging again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The WordPress.com stats helper monkeys prepared a 2014 annual report for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/2014/annual-report/&quot;&gt;[img 404]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an excerpt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A San Francisco cable car holds 60 people. This blog was viewed about &lt;strong&gt;3,100&lt;/strong&gt; times in 2014. If it were a cable car, it would take about 52 trips to carry that many people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/2014/annual-report/&quot;&gt;Click here to see the complete report.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Uncategorized" /></entry><entry><title type="html">My Way - Frank Sinatra</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/11/08/16-08-57-My_Way__Frank_Sinatra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Way - Frank Sinatra" /><published>2014-11-08T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-11-08T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/11/08/16-08-57-My_Way__Frank_Sinatra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/11/08/16-08-57-My_Way__Frank_Sinatra.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I did what I had to do And saw it through without exemption. I planned each charted course; Each careful step along the byway, And more, much more than this, I did it my way.-- Tagtag na empleyado&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para sa mga taong &lt;em&gt;solo flight&lt;/em&gt;, tumatapos ng mga responsibilidad ng mga pabaya, at &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seagull_manager&quot; title=&quot;Seagull manager - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;pinamumunuan ng mga &lt;em&gt;seagull&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, inaalay ko sa inyo ang awiting ito. Pampalubag-loob, nawa.https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6E2hYDIFDIU&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mabuha, mga martir.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paalala: Paabiso po sa &lt;em&gt;comments&lt;/em&gt; kung hindi na gumagana ang &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; sa taas, upang mapalitan. Maraming salamat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;duking [2014-11-09 10:35:31]
  Gumagana yung video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Videoke" /><category term="Videos" /><category term="frank sinatra" /><category term="martir" /><category term="my way" /><category term="seagull management" /><category term="seagull manager" /><category term="videoke" /><summary type="html">Para sa mga taong solo flight, tumatapos ng mga responsibilidad ng mga pabaya, at pinamumunuan ng mga seagull.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Grind With Me - Pretty Ricky [NSFW]</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/10/12/08-51-28-Grind_With_Me__Pretty_Ricky_NSFW.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Grind With Me - Pretty Ricky [NSFW]" /><published>2014-10-12T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-10-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/10/12/08-51-28-Grind_With_Me__Pretty_Ricky_NSFW</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/10/12/08-51-28-Grind_With_Me__Pretty_Ricky_NSFW.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Grind with me. - MRT passenger sa palabas na pasahero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para sa mga mananakay ng MRT, lalo na tuwing &lt;em&gt;rush hour&lt;/em&gt;.Lalong-lalo na sa mga bumababa sa mga istasyong walang gaanong &lt;em&gt;human traffic&lt;/em&gt;, gaya ng GMA-Kamuning at Santolan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mukhang ito ata ang nararapat na ipatugtog sa &lt;em&gt;intercom&lt;/em&gt; ng tren; pampalubag-loob sa mga pasaherong nag-a-ala-sardinas para lamang makarating sa paroroonan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/d7m\_od7YGzg&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ika nga ng kasabihan:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Trains: more fun in the Philippines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Videoke" /><category term="Videos" /><category term="grind with me" /><category term="mrt" /><category term="prety ricky" /><category term="videoke" /><summary type="html">Para sa mga mananakay ng MRT, lalo na tuwing rush hour.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hindi Kita Iiwan - Rey Valera</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/08/14/14-49-45-Hindi_Kita_Iiwan__Rey_Valera.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hindi Kita Iiwan - Rey Valera" /><published>2014-08-14T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2014-08-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/08/14/14-49-45-Hindi_Kita_Iiwan__Rey_Valera</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/videoke/videos/2014/08/14/14-49-45-Hindi_Kita_Iiwan__Rey_Valera.html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Tinangka nating mangarap sa mundong sadyang mapagkait. Ngunit ano man ang mangyari sa ating pagmamahalan, Mahal ko, laging umasa. Hindi kita iiwan. Hinding-hindi kita iiwan.-- Naniningil ng utang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Para sa mga naniningil, at sinisingil, ng utang.http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=frno7LToFIE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paalala: Paabiso po sa &lt;em&gt;comments&lt;/em&gt; kung hindi na gumagana ang &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; sa taas, upang mapalitan. Maraming salamat.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Videoke" /><category term="Videos" /><category term="hindi kita iiwan" /><category term="rey valera" /><category term="utang" /><category term="videoke" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Phones, Water, and Rice</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/scribbles/2013/08/26/04-51-12-Phones_Water_and_Rice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Phones, Water, and Rice" /><published>2013-08-26T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/scribbles/2013/08/26/04-51-12-Phones_Water_and_Rice</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/scribbles/2013/08/26/04-51-12-Phones_Water_and_Rice.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I had the unfortunate experience of dropping my Xperia Neo L in water (more like it slipping out of my pocket and dropping into my laundry tub). It was shocking and fun at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I managed to fish it out after about 3 seconds. It was not that soaked; however, everything is wet and the majority of the area of the screen is somewhat darker in color due to the water entering it. I proceeded to dry it all I can with a towel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I did some stupid things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I turned it on again.&lt;/strong&gt; I was really amazed that it was not short-circuited or anything, but noticed that the touch screen behaved erratically: it seems like invisible hands are treading on it constantly. But the phone still functions as usual: buttons still work, and it still responds to the headset buttons. I can still play audio, and when I plug in and out the headset, music plays and pauses respectively. (I have my phone configured to do that.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I tried to manually extract the water out of it by shaking it like a salt shaker.&lt;/strong&gt; I managed to extract some water out of the phone, but not all. It also left streak marks on the touch screen, easily viewable by tilting it upwards when the phone is on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As per suggestion, I tried to take it to a local repair station (not the Sony Service Center) for drying.&lt;/strong&gt; At this point I observed that as the phone dries the touch screen tends to return to normal (btw, before doing #2 the touch screen does not work; afterwards, it did with its erratic behaviour), and since I do not have the tools to open it I was hoping that the local repairman was cooperative enough to do this for me for a small amount. However, he seems not to know what he is talking about (he said about the screen needing total replacing), so there goes my help and an increase in dread that I need to go to the Sony Service Center to have this thing fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I bought some screwdrivers so that I can open this thing on my own.&lt;/strong&gt; Resolving not to go to the Sony Service Center before doing everything I can, I bought some tools at a total of about ₱300 and tried to open up the phone. I ended losing a screw and frustration for it won’t open.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goto 1. Repeatedly.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, that’s so stupid of me. But then, I resolved that my phone’s not really FUBAR and I just need to let it dry and I can use it again like normal. I was even ecstatic when I saw some moisture forming on the camera eye and the sides of the phone’s screen (not on the display, just the case that covers the screen), even though I could not wipe it off. I deduced that if I kept the phone hot enough (by its CPU heat) it will help in the drying process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime during the night I had the insight of googling about the problem, and saw that it was common with solutions not necessarily having to go to the Sony Service Center or replacing the screen or buying a new phone (plus I learned about the water damage indicator and that it’s now red, consequently voiding my warranty). And even though I know my phone is not that FUBAR, it gave me additional hope that the screen need not be replaced as the local repairman preached.That’s where rice comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/thread/127187?start=0&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot; title=&quot;Main: Xperia P dropped in water :'(&quot;&gt;The topmost result&lt;/a&gt; suggests rice to drive moisture out of the phone, with the stern precaution of not turning it on or even trying to. &lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/message/449062#449062&quot; title=&quot;Main: Phone Got Soaked In Water Now Malfunctioning&quot;&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://community.giffgaff.com/t5/giffgaff-Top-Tips/Dropped-your-phone-in-water/td-p/2138513&quot; title=&quot;Dropped your phone in water? - The giffgaff community&quot;&gt;sites&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/thread/3478?start=10&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot; title=&quot;Main: Just dropped my new phone in a bath of water - HELP!&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.xda-developers.com/showthread.php?t=1024537&quot; title=&quot;[Q] Dropped in water, how to fix? - xda-developers&quot;&gt;various&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/thread/50531?start=0&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot; title=&quot;Main: Dropped in water, touch not working&quot;&gt;suggestions&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikihow.com/Save-a-Wet-Cell-Phone&quot; title=&quot;How to Save a Wet Cell Phone: 13 Steps - wikiHow&quot;&gt;and&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://lifehacker.com/211623/save-your-wet-cell-phone&quot; title=&quot;Save your wet cell phone&quot;&gt;tales&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://androidqueries.com/best-thing-do-if-sony-xperia-s-dropped-water-11772.html&quot; title=&quot;Best thing to do if Sony Xperia S dropped in water? \| Android Troubleshooting&quot;&gt;later&lt;/a&gt;, being the Filipino I am, I resolved to buy a half-kilo of rice, crossed my fingers, buried my phone in it, and slept fitfully.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I also researched about desiccants. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desiccant&quot; title=&quot;Desiccant - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt; tells me that&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[a] &lt;strong&gt;desiccant&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hygroscopic&quot; title=&quot;Hygroscopic&quot;&gt;hygroscopic&lt;/a&gt; substance that induces or sustains a state of dryness (&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desiccation&quot; title=&quot;Desiccation&quot;&gt;desiccation&lt;/a&gt;) in its vicinity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hygroscopic&quot; title=&quot;Hygroscopy - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;hygroscopy&lt;/a&gt; means &amp;gt; … the ability of a substance to attract and hold &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Water&quot; title=&quot;Water&quot;&gt;water&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Molecule&quot; title=&quot;Molecule&quot;&gt;molecules&lt;/a&gt; from the surrounding &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_environment&quot; title=&quot;Natural environment&quot;&gt;environment&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/message/63451#63451&quot; title=&quot;Main: Just dropped my new phone in a bath of water - HELP!&quot;&gt;As a commenter succinctly puts it&lt;/a&gt;, &amp;gt; A bag of rice has a super dry, “please feed me moisture”, type of atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also finally learned what silica gel is, and why there are those little bags of “beads” in almost every shoebox. As &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.silicagelpackets.com/save-that-wet-cell-phone-iphone-droid&quot; title=&quot;Save That Wet Cell Phone!  - SilicaGelPackets.com&quot;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; puts it, &amp;gt; Silica gel is a “desiccant,” a substance that sucks up water in its environment. There are several different desiccants out there—clay, for example, which is what’s in a lot of cat litter. But silica gel is hands down one of the best desiccants going. That’s why it was in your shoebox. It absorbs the moisture that might otherwise ruin your new footwear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And maybe that’s also the reason why shoeboxes retain their factory smell.Anyway, after waking up this morning I excavated my phone from its ricey grave and turned it on. And what do you know, the rice worked! The rice managed to extract the moisture on the camera eye and on the sides of the screen, and somewhat diminished the streaks on the touch screen. Best of all, the touch screen is now working as usual. I buried it again and hopefully by tomorrow more moisture would be driven out (after all, the sites recommended burying it for at least 24 hours, not for about a meager 8-10 hours).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, this had been a shockingly very fun weekend. And what I have learned, dear Princess Celestia?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep a level head.&lt;/strong&gt; As with any emergency situation, some detachment is needed in order to make rational decisions. Panic won’t solve anything and may even worsen the problem and lead to blame passing, which does not solve anything. You’re not stupid for letting that phone meet water; it’s an accident (unless &lt;a href=&quot;http://talk.sonymobile.com/thread/130450?start=0&amp;amp;tstart=0&quot; title=&quot;Main: Xperia Go infiltrated by water&quot;&gt;you do it on purpose&lt;/a&gt;; in that case you should assume some level of responsibility for that deliberate decision).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Desiccants can save wet phones.&lt;/strong&gt; Just like the solution for a malware-laden diskette is not throwing it away and buying a new one but an anti-virus (as it is commonly known today), a phone is not necessarily FUBAR the time it decides to swim. Do not let the phone soak, wipe it gently and &lt;strong&gt;do not attempt to shake out the water&lt;/strong&gt; as it can cause further damage, bury it in a desiccant, cross your fingers, and pray to a divine being to save your phone (or just grab a beer and drown your worries away). And check on it after at least 24 hours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never turn on wet phones.&lt;/strong&gt; Or even try to. It’s tempting to do it to check if it still works, but water is a conductor of electricity and it may short out some internal circuitry and worsen the situation. Maybe I’m just lucky enough not to short anything serious, though I think I managed to short the flashlight mechanism because when I insert the battery the LED lights up but turns off as soon as I press the power button and stays that way when I shut down the phone.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not go to any service center until you have tried everything.&lt;/strong&gt; The Internet is a very useful forum; a little searching and literacy helps a lot. You’ll save a lot of money in the process, learn something new, and will help to keep the anxiety level down because nothing shoots it up the roof if the man you are talking about says you need to replace some parts or buy a new phone (let’s give him the benefit of the doubt that he/she is not taking advantage of the situation to rip off your hard-earned money).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Go to the service center if you have tried everything.&lt;/strong&gt; And do not try to hide the situation; remember the water indicator? It will just give you a very bad reputation, and nothing irks people more than when they see through a bold-faced lie. And when I say a service center, it should be the manufacturer’s accredited service center, not just some ad hoc vendor in the sidewalk claiming he/she can fix everything for you can end up with a brick and exorbitant service charges&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;And I forgot to mention, &lt;strong&gt;water damage voids a phone’s warranty&lt;/strong&gt;? Just like dropping it and breaking the screen as a result, water damage is considered user negligence. So there goes the free service charge. That’s why I recommend going to the service center last because it can cost a lot if you just surrender your waterlogged-phone to their technician (the moment they inspect it, their money meters start ticking).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of you wondering about the current status of my phone, well it does look somewhat good. - Touch is fully responsive now, just like before it decided to go on a swim.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The screen still has water streaks; hopefully I can still get it out with rice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As far as I can test, all are still functional. Buttons work; programs work. I haven’t tried to call or SMS anyone yet, as well as connecting to the Internet, GPS or Bluetooth. Maybe I’ll post an update on this, but (as far as this blog history goes) do not depend on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maybe the flashlight mechanism is short-circuited; I really don’t know.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lost a screw. Not really life-threatening, but one reason to completely void my warranty.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The water damage indicator is red. The main reason that voids my warranty. (Luckily there’s only 2 months left.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I have not tried to charge it yet; will try after the phone completely dries up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other things I have garnered from this experience: - &lt;strong&gt;A new appreciation for rice.&lt;/strong&gt; I am a Filipino, and rice is the staple of every household. So it tends to be a bit boring, especially if you are exposed to foreign cuisine and love pizza. That experience helped me appreciate rice more, for aside from saving lives it can also save gadgets. Now if it could only eliminate entirely the water marks on my touch screen…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovering silica gel.&lt;/strong&gt; Yes, I really don’t know they’re called as such, and I really don’t know what those funky packets they put in most boxes heavily laden with poison marks are and what they’re for. But now I know, and that I should store them for future use instead of discarding them. Just in case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovering the need for small screwdrivers.&lt;/strong&gt; I am a computer scientist so I don’t get to fiddle around with bare hardware often, but I realized the need to have spare tools for cases like this. Anyway, there’s no harm in having them stored in a secure container all the time somewhere, right? (Except maybe for rust, but that can easily be dealt with.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hmmnn, it seems like having your phone wet is not really a waste of time, and can be a source of knowledge for future references (and apparently blog entries). This reminds me of this Nichijou episode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;style&gt;.embed-container { position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden; max-width: 100%; } .embed-container iframe, .embed-container object, .embed-container embed { position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; }&lt;/style&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;embed-container&quot;&gt;    &lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/2-hEQrgJ5fc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you ever get your phone wet, here’s a motivational message for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2013/08/soakedphone.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2013-08-26-04-51-12-Phones_Water_and_Rice/soakedphone.png&quot; alt=&quot;soakedphone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Image of the rice tub from here: http://www.wikihow.com/Image:Save-a-Wet-Cell-Phone-Step-8.jpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But maybe, the best thing to save your phone from water death is &lt;strong&gt;not having it wet in the first place&lt;/strong&gt;. For starters, you can start by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wikihow.com/Temporarily-Waterproof-Your-PDA/Tablet/Phone&quot; title=&quot;How to Temporarily Waterproof Your PDA/Tablet/Phone: 13 Steps&quot;&gt;temporarily waterproofing your phone&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;related-articles&quot;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://gwenyvette.wordpress.com/2013/08/19/f270e3fd-cb7e-4178-a548-1f1fb53b705e_samsung-galaxy-s4-active-i-jpg/&quot;&gt;What to do if your phone got wet?&lt;/a&gt; (gwenyvette.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://davisintro.wordpress.com/2013/08/20/what-to-do-with-desiccant-silica-gel/&quot;&gt;What to Do With Desiccant Silica Gel&lt;/a&gt; (davisintro.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://soghettofabulous.wordpress.com/2013/07/30/how-to-fix-water-logged-cell-phones/&quot;&gt;How to Fix Water-Logged Cell Phones&lt;/a&gt; (soghettofabulous.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Scribbles" /><category term="Silica gel" /><category term="Sony" /><category term="Water" /><category term="wet phone" /><category term="xperia" /><category term="xperia neo l" /><summary type="html">Keep calm and submerge it in rice.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">World: EOT</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/events/scribbles/2013/01/05/14-26-36-World_EOT.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="World: EOT" /><published>2013-01-05T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2013-01-05T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/events/scribbles/2013/01/05/14-26-36-World_EOT</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/events/scribbles/2013/01/05/14-26-36-World_EOT.html">&lt;p&gt;This morning, while eating breakfast, I wondered about the status of the latest phenomenon to grip the world, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2012_phenomenon&quot; title=&quot;2012 phenomenon - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;the end of the Mayan bak’tun 13&lt;/a&gt; that was scheduled to occur on December 21, 2012 in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gregorian_calendar&quot; title=&quot;Gregorian calendar&quot;&gt;Gregorian calendar&lt;/a&gt;. During this date, it was prophesied that the world would end, wiping out civilization and mankind as we know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the date passed without the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Book_of_Revelation&quot; title=&quot;Book of Revelation&quot;&gt;book of Revelation&lt;/a&gt; fulfilling itself, and today is January 5. People are still reproducing, some restoring the environment while others continue destroying it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I proceeded to re-read the Wikipedia article about the issue, and was surprised by two changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The article is now written in past tense.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional sections were added, primarily describing what people around the world did days before and during December 21, 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also found a related article, Wikipedia’s “&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_dates_predicted_for_apocalyptic_events&quot; title=&quot;List of dates predicted for apocalyptic events - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;List of dates predicted for apocalyptic events&lt;/a&gt;”, which will be the main focus of this blog entry.Reading through that article, the first thing we notice is that there had been &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_dates_predicted_for_apocalyptic_events#Past_predictions&quot; title=&quot;List of dates predicted for apocalyptic events - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;numerous failed predictions for the end of the world in the past&lt;/a&gt;, with December 21, 2012 the latest to be added as of writing. Also, there is another &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_dates_predicted_for_apocalyptic_events#Future_predictions&quot; title=&quot;List of dates predicted for apocalyptic events - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;list of predictions with dates occurring in the future&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’d like to point out, however, is these predictions follow a certain format, a template, depicted as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ATTENTION!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO:&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone&lt;strong&gt;WHAT:&lt;/strong&gt; End of the world&lt;strong&gt;WHEN:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;date&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;WHERE:&lt;/strong&gt; Earth &lt;strong&gt;WHY:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;reasons&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;HOW:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;event&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;choices&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;BY:&lt;/strong&gt; &amp;lt;predictor&amp;gt; &lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong&gt; This is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that the process of coming up with these dates that can be summarized by the following flowchart.&lt;a href=&quot;http://quintophilosophy.files.wordpress.com/2013/01/endoftheworld.png&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2013-01-05-14-26-36-World_EOT/endoftheworld.png&quot; alt=&quot;End of the world flowchart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; End of the world flowchart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s examine deeper each pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction Template&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The template above can be broken down into two components: constants and variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The constants are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eschatology&quot; title=&quot;Eschatology&quot;&gt;End of the world predictions&lt;/a&gt; are almost always targeted to all of humankind, regardless of race, culture, nation, or religious orientation, much like a general announcement or an advertisement, though the scope may change (e.g., the destruction of the Roman empire).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHAT.&lt;/strong&gt; The subject does change its wording, but it always pertains to the end of times. As above, the scope may change.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHERE.&lt;/strong&gt; Of course, the “where” is always the Earth, in whole (e.g., the 2012 phenomenon) or in part (e.g., the predictions referring to the destruction of Rome), though I presume that if in the future mankind successfully colonized space, the “where” part will become a variable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER.&lt;/strong&gt; The last constant is the disclaimer, for as of writing, there are a total of 197 predictions listed on the page, with 187 of them failing to happen. Simple computation yields a 94.92% failure rate. But then, the computation is actually erroneous, for it assumes that 5.08% of the predictions are successes, and simple logic will dictate that you cannot count those future dates for the simple fact that they still have not passed. Thus, discarding the 10 future predictions, we come up with a 100% failure rate, which is consistent with the empirical fact that Earth, and civilization, is currently undestroyed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the variables: 1. &lt;strong&gt;WHEN.&lt;/strong&gt; This is actually the most entertaining variable, for this is the answer to the core question of when the world would end. As said above, many predicted dates have gone and past, and I sincerely believe that as long as there are people out there with too much free time on their hands, more dates would be cited as “the end of the world”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHY.&lt;/strong&gt; I believe this is the second most interesting variable, and the main reason that predictions don’t happen. I admit that I do not know by heart (or even by rote) all the events listed in the article, so based on what is listed in the tables, we can categorize the usual WHYs into the following:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Religious. Usually associated with the second coming. Predictions come from religious works such as the bible, oftentimes with the application of numerology and astrology.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Terrestrial. Usually about natural disasters predicting the second coming.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Astronomical. Usually about planetary and galactic alignments, and comets.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrial. Usually extraterrestrial “ambassadors” relaying alien messages.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;To those who want to know why these WHYs are almost always easily discredited, here are some of the answers.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Religious. For the Christians, the Lord explicitly states that &lt;a href=&quot;http://bible.cc/mark/13-32.htm&quot; title=&quot;Mark 13:32 &amp;quot;No one knows about that day or hour, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father.&quot;&gt;no one really knows except the Father&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://bible.cc/matthew/24-36.htm&quot; title=&quot;Matthew 24:36 &amp;quot;No one knows about that day or hour, not even the angels in heaven, nor the Son, but only the Father.&quot;&gt;when He will come again&lt;/a&gt;, since most of the religious predictions concern the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Second_Coming_of_Christ&quot; title=&quot;Second Coming of Christ&quot;&gt;second coming of Christ&lt;/a&gt;. I really don’t know what to counter for other religions not believing in Christ, or His Father (which is, in a way, sad, for it demonstrates my ignorance of other theistic paradigms).&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Terrestrial. These events are mostly predictable, and natural. That’s why they’re called “natural disasters”, for they happen naturally, regardless whether humans exist or not.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Astronomical. The usual argument here depends on what is being leveraged as to be the “cause” of the tribulation. For a real life example, you can visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nasa.gov/topics/earth/features/2012.html&quot; title=&quot;NASA - Beyond 2012: Why the World Didn't End&quot;&gt;NASA’s article about the 2012 phenomenon&lt;/a&gt; and read the astronomy-related causes supposed to bring about the destruction of the world last December 21, 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extraterrestrial. &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Extraterrestrial_life#Planetary_habitability_in_the_Solar_System&quot; title=&quot;Extraterrestrial life - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;So far, there have been no extraterrestrial life forms detected&lt;/a&gt;. Though the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Panspermia&quot; title=&quot;Panspermia - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;theory of panspermia&lt;/a&gt; attempts to explain how life on Earth came about (apart from others), this theory has not been conclusively proven as time of writing. Thus, these facts alone can discredit people who boast that they had received information on when the world will end. Please do notify me, however, if any of these have been proven THROUGH SCIENCE, not via crop circles and blurry images of lights during a foggy night.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Of course, I am not saying that these are the only reasons usually posted in the WHY section, but these are the usual ones. Usually, only the wording is modified.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HOW.&lt;/strong&gt; This variable describes how the apocalypse will take place, which can be through alien invasions, planetary collisions, or through events outlined in the book of Revelation. This variable usually expands the WHY variable through horrendous events, such as very strong earthquakes. This can be said as the third most interesting variable, and is often the source of ideas for entertainment firms such as Hollywood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TODO.&lt;/strong&gt; This usually tells people what they should do to survive the apocalypse or, in case of the second coming, how to be saved. Common TODOs include repentance and food stockpiling.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BY.&lt;/strong&gt; This is the person/s who has/have predicted the destruction. This is a very useful variable in my opinion, for sometimes it helps the public calm down when the person has a history of failed predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prediction Flowchart&lt;/strong&gt;It cannot actually be helped that there is such a thing as a “prediction flowchart”, since all predictions to date have failed (see the DISCLAIMER argument for discussion). The usual process is that when an initial prediction fails to pass, the predictor almost always says that he/she miscalculated/misinterpreted something, then proceeds to publish a revised date with an accompanying explanation of the encountered “anomaly”. A case in point is the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/2011_end_times_prediction&quot; title=&quot;2011 end times prediction - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;predictions of Harold Camping on 2011&lt;/a&gt;, which have cast fear upon the Filipino people during that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even the scientifically accepted date of the end of the world, the time when the sun expands to a red giant as it nears the end of its life, is not expressed in exact dates but in estimates. But then, it still can be said that this prediction follows the flowchart, for it may be revised as man gain more knowledge about the interactions of astronomical bodies in space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As far as end-of-the-world predictions go, we can only conclude the following facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No one knows the exact time when the world will end.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many more predictions will come and go until the world truly ends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then, maybe the business of predicting the end of the world is not a waste of time, after all. Just like the entertainment industry, it is somewhat an easy way to be famous, though some do become infamous after their predictions fail. They can also serve as a meter to “measure” public gullibility and ignorance of some basic phenomena, for in most predictions the implications of simple events, which really have no implications at all if experts are to be consulted (e.g., the gravitational effect of galactic and planetary alignments to Earth), are explained through esoteric waysConsulting again the Wikipedia article, it seems that the world is again due on May 19, 2013 according to Ronald Weinland. Following our template above, here is a summary of what he essentially talks about on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ronaldweinland.com/&quot; title=&quot;Ronald Weinland - Author of &amp;quot;The Prophesied End-Time&amp;quot; &amp;amp; &amp;quot;2008 - God's Final Witness&amp;quot; \| 	 Ronald Weinland&quot;&gt;his website&lt;/a&gt; (as of January 5, 2013).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ATTENTION!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WHO:&lt;/strong&gt; Everyone&lt;strong&gt;WHAT:&lt;/strong&gt; End of the world&lt;strong&gt;WHEN:&lt;/strong&gt; May 19, 2013 &lt;strong&gt;WHERE:&lt;/strong&gt; Earth &lt;strong&gt;WHY:&lt;/strong&gt; Second Coming of Christ &lt;strong&gt;HOW:&lt;/strong&gt; See book of Revelation*. &lt;strong&gt;TODO:&lt;/strong&gt; Repent and prepare &lt;strong&gt;BY:&lt;/strong&gt; Ronald Weinland** &lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong&gt; This is not true.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*This is an assumption, for his blog entries are really long and I’m not patient enough to read them. **According to Wikipedia, &lt;a href=&quot;en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Church_of_God_Preparing_for_the_Kingdom_of_God#2012.E2.80.932013_end-time_prophecy&quot; title=&quot;Church of God Preparing for the Kingdom of God - Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&quot;&gt;this is his third prediction&lt;/a&gt;.Let’s see each other again on May 20, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;related-articles&quot;&gt;Related articles&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.confused.com/life-insurance/articles/will-the-world-end-in-2012&quot;&gt;I’m Confused.com: Will the world end in 2012?&lt;/a&gt; (confused.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://notesofnearlyeverything.wordpress.com/2012/12/02/a-brief-ish-history-on-the-end-of-the-world/&quot;&gt;A brief-ish History on the end of the World..&lt;/a&gt; (notesofnearlyeverything.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://news.discovery.com/space/extraterrestrial-oceans-may-offer-best-chance-for-finding-genesis-ii-121227.html&quot;&gt;Genesis II: Extraterrestrial Oceans Could Host Life&lt;/a&gt; (news.discovery.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fasab.wordpress.com/2012/12/23/so-how-can-you-tell-mayan-bollocks-from-ordinary-bollocks/&quot;&gt;So How Can You Tell Mayan Bollocks From Ordinary Bollocks?&lt;/a&gt; (fasab.wordpress.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://listverse.com/2012/12/21/10-doomsday-predictions-beyond-2012/&quot;&gt;10 Doomsday Predictions Beyond 2012&lt;/a&gt; (listverse.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;[Russian PM not joking - extraterrestrials among us according to MIB documentary - Honolulu exopolitics&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Examiner.com](http://2012indyinfo.com/2013/01/03/russian-pm-not-joking-extraterrestrials-among-us-according-to-mib-documentary-honolulu-exopolitics-examiner-com/) (2012indyinfo.com)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.history.com/news/2011/05/17/apocalypses-that-weren%e2%80%99t/&quot;&gt;Apocalypses That Weren’t&lt;/a&gt; (history.com)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;table&gt;
      &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;[Extraterrestrial Life elsewhere in universe&lt;/td&gt;
          &lt;td&gt;Are we alone?](http://zainullabiddin.wordpress.com/2012/12/24/extraterrestrial-life-elsewhere-in-universe-are-we-alone/) (zainullabiddin.wordpress.com)&lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
      &lt;/tbody&gt;
    &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Events" /><category term="Scribbles" /><category term="2012 phenomenon" /><category term="21 December 2012" /><category term="end of the world" /><category term="Eschatology" /><category term="Prediction" /><category term="Second Coming of Christ" /><summary type="html">When will the world really end?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2012 in review</title><link href="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2012/12/31/08-40-14-2012_in_review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2012 in review" /><published>2012-12-31T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2012-12-31T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2012/12/31/08-40-14-2012_in_review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://arden-chan.ml/uncategorized/2012/12/31/08-40-14-2012_in_review.html">&lt;p&gt;The WordPress.com stats helper monkeys prepared a 2012 annual report for this blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/2012/annual-report/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/assets/images/2012-12-31-08-40-14-2012_in_review/2012-emailteaser.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an excerpt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;600 people reached the top of Mt. Everest in 2012. This blog got about &lt;strong&gt;2,600&lt;/strong&gt; views in 2012. If every person who reached the top of Mt. Everest viewed this blog, it would have taken 4 years to get that many views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://arden-chan.ml/2012/annual-report/&quot;&gt;Click here to see the complete report.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;comments&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>garuruchan</name></author><category term="Uncategorized" /><summary type="html">From Wordpress.com</summary></entry></feed>